leftronic.com 2018-08-29

# AppDirect Privacy Notice - AppDirect

Updated: May 22, 2018

Welcome, and thank you for your interest in AppDirect, Inc. and our products, applications, and services. This Privacy Notice describes how AppDirect, Inc. (together with its subsidiaries, "AppDirect," "we," "us," or "our"), collects, uses, and discloses information obtained through [www.appdirect.com](http://www.appdirect.com/), [www.appinsights.com](http://www.appinsights.com/), and [www.appwise.com](http://www.appwise.com/) (the "Websites"), and our software offerings, including our application marketplace ("AppDirect Marketplace"), data insights product ("AppInsights") and our search and messaging application ("AppWise") and how you can exercise your data privacy rights. This Privacy Notice also applies to any other applications, products, services, or websites operated by AppDirect that link to this Privacy Notice (collectively with the Websites, AppDirect Marketplace, AppInsights, and AppWise, the "Services").

Third parties who promote and market AppDirect branded or white-labeled instances of the AppDirect Marketplace are referred to in this Privacy Notice as "Syndication Partners." The AppDirect Marketplace allows independent software and application vendors (each, a "Developer") to make certain features of their software as a service applications, or other product or service owned and operated by Developer (each, a "Developer Application") available to you through the AppDirect Marketplace. This Privacy Notice does not address the collection, uses, and disclosures of your information by Syndication Partners or Developers. These entities have their own policies describing their practices that, to the extent applicable, we encourage you to read. 

**We provide you choices that allow you to opt-out or control how we use and share your data.**  

**QUICK LINKS**

We recommend that you read this Privacy Notice in full to ensure you are fully informed.  However, if you only want to access a particular section of this Privacy Notice, then you can click on the relevant link below to jump to that section. 

1. The information AppDirect collects    
2. How we use your information   
3\. Legal basis for processing personal information (EEA visitors only)  
4\. How we may disclose your information   
5. Transfer and processing   
6\. Your choices and rights   
7. Third party services   
8. Data security   
9\. Data retention   
10\. Changes and updates to this Privacy Notice:   
11\. Contact information

## 1\. The information AppDirect collects

**Information You Voluntarily Provide**. We collect any information that you provide us when you use the Services. 

  * Registration and Profile Information: If you register for one of our Services, we will ask you to provide your name, email address, and title. You may optionally provide additional profile information such as your phone number, date of birth, IM screen name, Twitter handle, and professional experience. You may also submit content including text, images, and other media files (“User Submissions”), such as when you submit a comment regarding a Developer Application. 
  * Information Provided through AppWise or AppInsights: If you connect AppWise or AppInsights to third party cloud-based services, you authorize and enable us to access your third party cloud-based services and the content contained on those services in order to provide the Services and to provide you with productivity tools. AppWise and/or AppInsights retrieves the data maintained by these third party cloud-based services and copies it in a different format to AppDirect-controlled servers. The data can then be stored, aggregated, modified, removed, or provided to other users in case you are sharing content with other users. This allows us to provide you with search and data analytics functionality for your data. The type of data copied to AppDirect-controlled servers depends entirely on the type of data you store and maintain in the third-party cloud-based services. You can disconnect any third party cloud-based services at any time. Once disconnected, AppDirect will no longer aggregate data from that service. 
  * Communications and Other Interactions: We may collect information you provide if you interact with other users through the Services. We may also collect information through your communications with our customer-support team. 
  * Payments: If you make payments through the Services, we will ask you to provide your payment information, such as your credit card number, so our service providers can process your payments. 

**Information We Collect When You Use Our Services**. We may automatically collect certain technical information from your computer or mobile device when you use the Services. 

  * Device and Usage Information: When you use the Services or open one of our HTML emails, we may automatically record certain information from your web browser by using different types of technology, including standard log files, "clear gifs" or "web beacons." This automatically collected information may include Internet Protocol address ("IP Address") or other device address or ID, web browser and/or device type, the web pages or sites that you visit just before or just after you visit the Services, the pages you view on the Services, and the dates and times that you visit the Services. 
  * Cookies: When you use the Services, we may send one or more cookies – small text files containing a string of alphanumeric characters – to your computer. Cookies help us to operate and improve our services, customize your experience and preferences, allow you to access and use our services without re-entering your email and password and to understand which areas and features of our services are most popular and count visits. We may use both session cookies and persistent cookies. A session cookie disappears after you close your browser. A persistent cookie remains after you close your browser and may be used by your browser on subsequent visits. Persistent cookies can be removed. Please review your web browser "Help" file to learn the proper way to modify your cookie settings. Please note that if you delete, or choose not to accept, cookies from the Services, you may not be able to utilize the features of the Services to their fullest potential. Syndicated Partners may send cookies to your computer in order to track your online activities on the Services. We are not responsible for the practices and policies of Syndicated Partners and encourage you to learn more about a Syndicated Partner's privacy and security policies.

Analytics and Ad Networks. We use website and application analytics services provided by internal and third parties that use cookies and other similar technologies to collect information about the use of our Services and to report trends, without identifying individual visitors. The third parties that provide us with these services may also collect information about your use of third-party websites. 

We use Google Analytics, a web analytics service provided by Google, Inc. ("Google"). Google Analytics uses cookies. The information generated by the cookie about your use of the website (including your IP address) will be transmitted to and stored by Google on servers in the United States. In case of activation of the IP anonymization, Google will truncate/anonymize the last octet of the IP address for Member States of the European Union as well as for other parties to the Agreement on the European Economic Area. Only in exceptional cases, the full IP address is sent to and shortened by Google servers in the USA. On behalf of the website provider Google will use this information for the purpose of evaluating your use of the website, compiling reports on website activity for website operators and providing other services relating to website activity and internet usage to the website provider. Google will not associate your IP address with any other data held by Google. You may refuse the use of cookies by selecting the appropriate settings on your browser. However, please note that if you do this, you may not be able to use the full functionality of our website. Furthermore, you can prevent Google's collection and use of data (cookies and IP address) by downloading and installing the Google Analytics opt-out browser add-on available at <https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout>.

You can also refuse the use of Google Analytics by clicking on the following link. An opt-out cookie will be set on the computer, which prevents the future collection of your data when visiting this website: 

<a href=“javascript:gaOptout()“>Disable Google Analytics</a>

For further information concerning the terms and conditions of use and data privacy please visit: <https://www.google.com/analytics/terms/us.html> or <https://www.google.com/policies/>. Please note that on this website, Google Analytics code is supplemented by "anonymizeIp" to ensure an anonymized collection of IP addresses (so called IP-masking).

We may also allow ad network providers to set and access their own cookies, pixel tags and similar technologies to collect information about your use of the Services. These network advertisers may use this and other information they have collected about you to deliver targeted advertisements for products and services in which you might be interested. If you prefer to not receive targeted advertising, you can opt-out of some network advertising programs that use your information. To do so please visit the Digital Advertising Alliance (DAA) Opt-Out Page: <http://www.aboutads.info/choices>.

Please note that even if you choose to remove your information (opt-out), you will still see advertisements. Additionally, many network advertising programs allow you to view and manage the interest categories they have compiled from your online browsing activities. These interest categories help determine the types of targeted advertisements you may receive. The DAA Opt-Out Page provides a tool that identifies its member companies that have cookies on your browser and provides links to those companies. 

**Information from Other Sources.** We may also obtain information from third parties and sources other than the Services, such as advertisers, Syndication Partners, Developers, or reseller partners, that we combine with information collected through the Services. We do so only where we have checked that these third parties either have your consent or are otherwise legally permitted or required to disclose your personal information to us. The types of information we collect from third parties include company roles and system identification numbers and we use the information we receive from these third parties to the extent necessary to provide the Services or maintain and/or improve the accuracy of the records we hold about you.

## 2\. How we use your information

**Service Related Usage.** We use the information we collection about and from you for a number of purposes, including: providing, operating, supporting, and improving the Services. Without limiting the generality of the foregoing, we use information provided by users in connection with integration of the Services with the applicable Syndication Partners' and Developers' services.

**Account Customization and Analytics**. AppDirect uses the information that you provide or that we collect to understand and analyze the usage trends and preferences of our users, to improve the way the Services work and look, and to create new features and functionality. For example, we may use the information collected to: (a) personalize our services, such as remembering your information so that you will not have to re-enter it during your visit or the next time you use the Services; (b) provide customized third party advertisements, content, and information; (c) monitor and analyze the effectiveness of our and third party marketing activities; (d) monitor aggregate site usage metrics such as total number of visitors and pages viewed; and (e) help us identify potential new products and services.

**Communications**. We use your information to communicate with you, in accordance with your communication preferences. For example, we will use your email address to contact you for information purposes such as account management, customer service, or system maintenance. In addition, AppDirect may use push notifications or your contact information to send information about your account such as when you receive a message, comment, or request from another user.

**Marketing**. We may use information we collect for marketing purposes, such as providing you with promotional materials that may be useful, relevant, valuable or otherwise of interest to you, in accordance with your marketing preferences. Where required under applicable law, we will obtain your prior opt-in consent to send you electronic marketing communications. You will have the ability to opt-out of receiving any such communications, either through unsubscribe links provided in the messages, by updating your account preferences, or by contacting us using the contact details provided under the "Contact Information" heading below.

## 3\. Legal basis for processing personal information (EEA visitors only)

If you are a resident from the European Economic Area, our legal basis for collecting and using the personal information described above will depend on the personal information concerned and the specific context in which we collect it. 

However, we will normally collect personal information from you only where we have your consent to do so, where we need the personal information to perform a contract with you, or where the processing is in our legitimate interests and not overridden by your data protection interests or fundamental rights and freedoms.  In some cases, we may also have a legal obligation to collect personal information from you.

If we ask you to provide personal information to comply with a legal requirement or to perform a contract with you, we will make this clear at the relevant time and advise you whether the provision of your personal information is mandatory or not (as well as of the possible consequences if you do not provide your personal information). 

Similarly, if we collect and use your personal information in reliance on our legitimate interests (or those of any third party), we will make clear to you at the relevant time what those legitimate interests are.

If you have questions about or need further information concerning the legal basis on which we collect and use your personal information, please contact us using the contact details provided under the “Contact Information” heading below.

## 4\. How we may disclose your information

AppDirect is not in the business of selling your information to direct marketers. We do, however, disclose your information, including personal information, in a variety of circumstances in connection with the operation of our business. We may also disclose your information with your permission. 

**Syndication Partners and Developers.** AppDirect discloses the information you provide or that we collect to Developers and Syndication Partners in connection with the interoperation of their service offerings with the Services in order for them to provide their services to you. AppDirect may provide Developers, applicable Syndication Partners, and your subscribing organization with information regarding your use of the Services.

**Service Providers.** AppDirect works with third party service providers who provide website development, hosting, maintenance, and support as well as other business services for us. To the extent it is necessary for these service providers to provide the services, these third parties may have access to or process your information.

**Other Users.** The Services allow users to communicate in a variety of ways. Any information that you voluntarily choose to include in an area on the Services that is accessible to another user, such as a public profile page or in a review, comment, posting, electronic message, or other User Submission, will be available to other users who have access to that content. Once you make your information available to others in any of these ways, it may be collected, used, and disclosed by the recipients without restriction.

**Employers.** If your employer is enrolled with AppWise, and you sign up for AppWise using your employer email account, we will report information to your employer's administrator such as service usage statistics that may include names of most active users, top search terms that are used, number of documents indexed and services that are accessed.

**Aggregate Data.** AppDirect may disclose aggregate non-identifiable information with interested third parties, to assist such parties in understanding the usage, viewing, and demographic patterns for certain programs, content, services, advertisements, promotions, and/or functionality on the Services.

**Third Party Applications.** We may enable you to share information from the Services to third party applications. We are not responsible for how you share this information through these or similar services. These third parties may use or share your information in accordance with their own privacy policies. We strongly suggest you review the third parties’ privacy policies if you use the relevant features.

**As Required by Law and Similar Disclosures.** We may disclose information about you: (i) if we are required to do so by law, regulation, or legal process, such as a court order or subpoena; (ii) in response to requests by government agencies, such as law enforcement authorities; (iii) when we believe disclosure is necessary or appropriate to protect the rights, property, or safety of AppDirect, our users and partners, or the public; and (iv) to enforce our agreements, policies, and Terms of Service.

**Merger, Sale, or Other Asset Transfers.** We reserve the right to transfer your information to service providers, advisors, potential transactional partners, or other third parties in connection with the consideration, negotiation, or completion of a corporate transaction in which we are acquired by or merged with another company or we sell, liquidate, or transfer all or a portion of our assets.

## 5\. Transfer and processing

If you are visiting or using the Services from the European Economic Area or other regions with laws governing data collection and use, please note that we may transfer your information to recipients in countries other than the country in which the information was originally collected, including the United States of America, where AppDirect is headquartered. Those countries may not have the same data protection laws as the country in which you initially provided the information. When we transfer your information to other countries, we will protect that information as described in this Privacy Notice. Specifically, we have implemented the European Commission’s Standard Contractual Clauses for transfers of personal information between our group companies (to the extent applicable), which require all group companies to protect personal information they process from the EEA in accordance with European Union data protection law. 

Our Standard Contractual Clauses can be provided on request. We have implemented similar appropriate safeguards with our third party service providers and partners and further details can be provided upon request.

## 6\. Your choices and rights

If you do not want the Services to collect information through the use of cookies, your browser may allow you to be notified when you receive certain types of cookies and restrict or disable certain cookies. Each browser is different, so you should check your browser’s "Help" menu to learn how to change your cookie preferences. Please be aware that if you disable or reject cookies, some features and Services may not work properly. You can opt-out of receiving further promotional messages from us by following the unsubscribe instructions provided in the promotional email you receive or by contacting us directly. Currently, the Services do not respond to your web browser "do not track" signals or other mechanisms. If, in the future, AppDirect creates a program or protocol to respond to such web browser "do not track" signals, we will inform you of the details of that protocol in this Privacy Notice. 

Subject to applicable law, you may have the right to: obtain confirmation that we hold information about you, request access to information we maintain about you, request portability of your personal information, ask us to restrict processing of your personal information, receive copies of the information we maintain about you, update and correct inaccuracies in your information, object to the processing of your information, and have the information blocked, anonymized or deleted, as appropriate. You may also have the right to withdraw any consent you previously provided to us. These rights may be limited in some circumstances by local law requirements.

You have the right to complain to a data protection authority about our collection and use of your personal information.  For more information, please contact your local data protection authority. Contact details for data protection authorities in the European Economic Area are available [here](http://ec.europa.eu/justice/data-protection/article-29/structure/data-protection-authorities/index_en.htm).

You may exercise your choices and rights by editing your information in your account page, if applicable, or by submitting a request to [privacy@appdirect.com](mailto:privacy@appdirect.com) or by contacting us using the contact details provided under the "Contact Information" heading below. You should be aware that it is not always possible to completely remove or delete all of your information from our databases without some residual data remaining in our archives because of backups because we are legally required to retain your data. To protect your privacy and security, we take steps to verify your identity before granting you account access or making corrections to your information. YOU ARE RESPONSIBLE FOR MAINTAINING THE SECRECY OF YOUR UNIQUE PASSWORD AND ACCOUNT INFORMATION AT ALL TIMES.

## 7\. Third party services

The Services contain links to and integrate with websites and services provided by third parties, including without limitation Developers and Syndication Partners (where applicable). Any information you provide on third party sites or services is provided directly to that third party and is subject to that third party's policies, if any, governing privacy and security. We are not responsible for the content or privacy and security practices and policies of third party sites or services to which links are displayed on the Services. We encourage you to learn about third parties’ privacy and security policies before providing them with your information.

## 8\. Data security

AppDirect makes use of appropriate physical, managerial, and technical measures in our efforts to safeguard the integrity and security of your personal information. We cannot, however, ensure or warrant the security of any information you transmit to AppDirect, and you do so at your own risk. Once we receive your transmission of information, AppDirect endeavors to secure our systems, but please note that this is not a guarantee that such information may not be accessed, disclosed, altered, or destroyed by system malfunction or circumvention of our safeguards.

## 9\. Data retention

We retain personal information we collect from you where we have an ongoing legitimate business need to do so (for example, to provide you with a service you have requested or to comply with applicable legal, tax or accounting requirements). 

When we have no ongoing legitimate business need to process your personal information, we will either delete or anonymise it or, if this is not possible (for example, because your personal information has been stored in backup archives), then we will securely store your personal information and isolate it from any further processing until deletion is possible. 

## 10\. Changes and updates to this Privacy Notice:

Please revisit this page periodically to stay aware of any changes to this Privacy Notice, which may be revised from time to time at AppDirect's sole discretion. If we modify the Privacy Notice, we will make it available through the Services, and indicate the date of the latest revision. In the event that the modifications materially alter your rights or obligations hereunder we will notify you as may be required by law.

Our amended Privacy Notice will automatically take effect 30 days after it is made available through the Services, except that (i) we will not, without your consent, use your previously collected personal information in a manner inconsistent with the Privacy Notice in effect when we received that information, and (ii) if you do not agree with any changes to the Privacy Notice, you may terminate your account ceasing use of the Services.

## 11\. Contact information

If you have any questions, concerns or complaints regarding the use or disclosure of your information or if you would like to review, delete or update information we have about you or your preferences, you can contact us either by mail or email:

AppDirect, Inc., Attn. Privacy Office    
650 California Street, Floor 25   
San Francisco, CA 94108   
USA

AppDirect Germany GmbH, Attn. Privacy Office   
Nymphenburger Str. 4   
80335 München Germany
